[Terms of Service](https://runalyze.com/en/legal/tos) | Privacy Policy | [Legal notice](https://runalyze.com/en/legal/notice)

Statement of Privacy
====================

Version: 20.02.2023

Scope
-----

**Responsible body within the meaning of data protection laws, in particular the EU basic data protection regulation (GDPR)**  
Runalyze GmbH  
Hochstraße 11  
67700 Niederkirchen  
Authorized representative managers: Hannes Christiansen, Michael Pohl  
michael@runalyze.com | hannes@runalyze.com  
+49 151 42011855  

We take the protection of your personal data very seriously and strictly adhere to the rules of data protection laws. Personal data is collected in RUNALYZE and on the RUNALYZE blog only to the extent necessary for technical and application purposes. Under no circumstances will the collected data be sold or passed on to third parties.

This data protection guideline explains which personal data we collect about you while you are on our pages as a visitor or user. To register on Runalyze, you must accept the privacy policy in order to use the service. By browsing the pages and services, the user agrees to the privacy policy and all subsequent revisions.

This privacy policy applies to the following domains:

* runalyze.de
* runalyze.com
* runalyze.dk
* runalyze.pl
* runalyze.info
* runalyze.biz
* runalyze.net
* runalyze.org

The legal basis of data protection can be found in the Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG), the Telemedia Act (TMG) and the EU Data Protection Ordinance (GDPR).

Personal information
--------------------

Personal data is information that can be used to identify a person, i.e. information that can be traced back to a person. This includes your name, email address or telephone number. Personal data also includes information about preferences, hobbies, memberships or which websites have been viewed by someone else.

Personal data will only be collected, used and passed on by the provider if this is permitted by law or if the user consents to the data collection.

The following mandatory information must be provided when registering on runalyze.com:

* Username
* Mail address

The following optional information can also be entered during registration, but can also be deleted afterwards:

* First- and Surname
* Year of birth
* Gender

After registration, further user data can be collected at RUNALYZE:

* Body values
    * Weight
    * Resting/Maximum heart rate
    * Body parts of fat, water, muscles and bones
    * Sleep (time, duration, quality, ...)
    * Further body values (HRV, mental state, blood pressure, blood glucose, menstrual cycle, ...)
* Activities (e. g. time, length, duration, altimeter, GPS data, heart rate, heart rate variability, performance data, additionally recorded data from sensors, tags, weather data, title, notes, ...)
* Equipment
* Goals
* ... and some more

### Cookie Declaration

### How we use the information

Information stored on Runalyze.com is used to operate and administer the site. The processed data is used to improve and correct the functionality of the service.

Access data/server log files
----------------------------

The provider (or its hosting provider) collects data about every access to the offer (so-called server log files). Access data includes: Name of the accessed website, file, date and time of access, amount of data transferred, notification of successful access, browser type and version, the user's operating system, referrer URL (the previously visited page), anonymized IP address and the requesting provider.

The provider uses the protocol data only for statistical evaluations for the purpose of operation, security and optimisation of the offer. However, the provider reserves the right to check the log data subsequently if there is a justified suspicion of illegal use based on concrete indications.

Contacting
----------

When contacting the provider (e.g. by means of a contact form or mail) the user's details are stored for the purpose of processing the enquiry and in the event that follow-up questions arise.

Comments and posts (on the blog)
--------------------------------

If users leave comments on the blog or other posts, their IP addresses are stored. This is done for the security of the provider, if someone writes illegal contents in comments and contributions (sworn, forbidden political propaganda, etc.). In this case the provider can be prosecuted for the comment or contribution and is therefore interested in the identity of the author.

Integration of third-party services and content
-----------------------------------------------

It is possible that third-party content such as videos from YouTube, maps from Google Maps, RSS feeds or graphics from other websites may be included in this online offer. This always presupposes that the providers of this content (hereinafter referred to as "third-party providers") perceive the IP address of the users. Without the IP address, they would not be able to send the content to the browser of the respective user. The IP address is therefore required for the presentation of this content. We make every effort to use only those contents whose respective providers use the IP address solely for the delivery of the contents. However, we have no influence if the third-party providers store the IP address for statistical purposes, for example. As far as we know, we inform the users about this.

### Google Maps

This offer uses Google Maps, which is operated by Google Inc, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States ("Google"). When a user visits a website that displays a map of Google Maps, the browser establishes a direct connection to Google's servers. According to Google, no personal data is collected without a click on the button. Only with logged in members, such data, among other things the IP address, are raised and processed.

The purpose and scope of the data collection and the further processing and use of the data by Google as well as your relevant rights and setting options for the protection of your privacy can be seen by the users of Google [Terms of Use](https://www.google.com/intl/de_en/help/terms_maps.html) for Google Maps.

### OpenStreetMap

This offer uses OpenStreetMap (OSM) to display gps data. Openstreetmap does not store user data. Further information can be found at [openstreetmap.org](https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Legal_FAQ).

### Mapbox

This offer uses Mapbox to display gps data. For displaying the gps data, the browser establishes a direct connection to the Mapbox server. Further information can be found in the [Terms of Use of Mapbox](https://www.mapbox.com/tos/).

### DarkSky (Weather) API

This offer uses the API of DarkSky to retrieve weather data. A single coordinate as well as the time of the activity is transmitted to DarkSky. No further information is transmitted. Further information can be found in the [Terms of Use](https://darksky.net/dev/docs/terms) and the [Privacy Policy](https://darksky.net/dev/docs/privacy) of DarkSky.

### Visual Crossing (Weather) API

This offer uses the API of [Visualcrossing](https://www.visualcrossing.com/) to retrieve weather data. A single coordinate as well as the time of the activity is transmitted to Visual Crossing. No further information is transmitted. Further information can be found in the [Terms of Use](https://www.visualcrossing.com/weather-services-terms) and the [Privacy Policy](https://www.visualcrossing.com/privacy) of Visual Crossing.

### Apple Weatherkit (Weather) API

This offer uses the API of Apples Weatherkit API to retrieve weather data. A single coordinate as well as the time of the activity is transmitted to Apple Weatherkit. No further information is transmitted. Further information can be found on the [Weatherkit information page](https://developer.apple.com/weatherkit/#:~:text=Privacy%20first,is%20never%20tracked%20between%20requests.) and the [Privacy Policy](https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/) by Apple.

### OpenWeatherMap

This offer uses the interface of OpenWeatherMap to retrieve weather data. A single coordinate and the time of the activity is transmitted to OpenWeatherMap. No further information is transmitted. Further information can be found in the [Terms of Use](https://openweathermap.org/terms), and the [Privacy Policy](https://openweathermap.org/privacy-policy) of OpenWeatherMap.

### Bunny.net

This offer uses [Bunny.net](https://bunny.net/?ref=5bdprloq0u) (a CDN provider) to deliver the content to the user faster. Client IP addresses are anonymized. Further information can be found in the [Privacy policy](https://bunny.net/privacy/) and [GDPR section](https://bunny.net/gdpr/).

### Gravatar

We use the profile picture service [Gravatar](https://gravatar.com/). Gravatar uses as image URL the mail address as MD5 hashed. To better protect the mail address, the hashed mail address is only forwarded internally to Gravatar via our CDN provider. No client IP is forwarded to Gravatar. Further information about Gravatar can be found in the [Privacy policy of Gravatar (Automattic).](https://automattic.com/privacy/)

You can enable and disable the use of Gravatar in [your account settings](https://runalyze.com/settings/account).

### Twitter

This site uses the buttons of the Twitter service. These buttons are provided by Twitter Inc, 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. They are recognizable by terms such as "Twitter" or "sequence", combined with a stylized blue bird. With the help of the buttons it is possible to share a post or page of this offer on Twitter or to follow the provider on Twitter.

When a user accesses a website on this website that contains such a button, his browser establishes a direct connection to Twitter's servers. The content of the Twitter button is transmitted directly from Twitter to the user's browser. The provider therefore has no influence on the amount of data Twitter collects with the help of this plugin and informs users according to their level of knowledge. After this only the IP address of the user the URL of the respective web page is transmitted with the purchase of the Buttons, but not for other purposes, than the representation of the Buttons, used.

Further information can be found in the Twitter data protection declaration at [https://twitter.com/privacy](https://twitter.com/privacy).

### Google AdSense

This offer uses Google AdSense, a service for integrating ads from Google Inc. "("Google"). Google AdSense uses "cookies", which are text files placed on the user's computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. Google AdSense also uses so-called web beacons (invisible graphics). These web beacons can be used to evaluate information such as visitor traffic on the pages of this website.

The information generated by cookies and web beacons about the use of this website (including the IP address of the users) and delivery of advertising formats is transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. This information may be passed on by Google to Google's contractual partners. However, Google will not merge your IP address with other data stored by you.

Users may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on their browser, however, the provider points out to users that in this case they may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, users consent to the processing of data about them by Google in the manner and for the purposes described above.

### Paddle (payment provider)

This offer uses the payment provider Paddle for the fulfillment of subscriptions. Upon completion, we receive information about which account has taken out which subscription and whether the payment was successful. All payment information are only at our payment provider. All further information can be found in the [Privacy Policy](https://paddle.com/privacy/) at Paddle.

Newsletter
----------

If you subscribe to the newsletter on this page, you have to enter your e-mail address. Specifying the name is optional. By entering your e-mail address you agree that you may subscribe to our newsletter and we may send you news.

After opening the first confirmation e-mail, which asks you to confirm your subscription to the newsletter again, as well as opening further newsletters, the following information will be sent directly to us:

* Whether a mail has been opened by a subscriber
* Which links subscribers clicked on (and the frequency)

This data is used for the administration and statistical evaluation of the newsletter in order to be able to optimise the offers even better. By subscribing to the newsletter you agree to this use of your data. We do not use the data for any other purpose. This data will not be passed on to third parties.

RUNALYZE uses the Amazon Simple Email Service (Amazon SES) to send the newsletter. (AWS). For the purpose of sending the newsletter, the e-mail addresses of the users are temporarily (during sending) transmitted to a server (within the EU) of AWS. Further information on Amazon SES and the use and processing of data by AWS is available at http://aws.amazon.com/de/ses/ and http://aws.amazon.com/de/privacy/.

Revocation, changes, corrections and updates
--------------------------------------------

The user has the right, upon request and free of charge, to receive information about the personal data stored about him. In addition, the user has the right to correction of incorrect data, blocking and deletion of his personal data, insofar as there is no legal obligation to store such data.

Regulatory Agency
-----------------

They may lodge a complaint with their competent supervisory authority. The supervisory authority is based on the federal state in which you reside. Find the address of the supervisory authority on the BFDI website: [https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften\_Links/anschriften\_links-node.html.](https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften_Links/anschriften_links-node.html)

[Datenschutz-Muster von Rechtsanwalt Thomas Schwenke - I LAW it](https://rechtsanwalt-schwenke.de/smmr-buch/datenschutz-muster-generator-fuer-webseiten-blogs-und-social-media/)

Further information
-------------------

If there are any questions left unanswered by this data protection declaration or if more detailed information is required on any point, please do not hesitate to contact us.

**RUNALYZE**  English Deutsch Polski Català Nederlandse Italiano Español Français Norsk suomi 中文 (33％已翻译) русский Hungarian (50%) Česky Português Português Brasileiro **Follow us**

**Customer Care**

**Documentation**

**Tools**

**About**

**Legal**
